<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Musically Geeky]]></title>
  <link href="http://markmccoy.us/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://markmccoy.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-02-08T15:55:34-06:00</updated>
  <id>http://markmccoy.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark McCoy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[when work becomes fun and vice versa]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/02/08/when-work-becomes-fun-and-vice-versa/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-08T17:02:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/02/08/when-work-becomes-fun-and-vice-versa</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>So I have been asked by my lovely wife to help her out with a project that she
wants to do at her job.   I can&#8217;t say too much about it, but it requires some
custom software to be written.  We sat down the other day and sketched out some
initial ideas of what the software would need to do, and how the users would
use the software (initially just her and a couple others, but later on it could
be the entire organization).</p>

<p>I guess I got a little excited because I immediately jumped into the project
full bore.  I don&#8217;t think she was prepared for that.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>I am what most people would term a geek or a nerd.  I&#8217;m cool with that.
Margaret knew that I was geeky when we met but I have rarely indulged my &#8220;inner
geek&#8221;.  In fact, my &#8220;inner geek&#8221; hasn&#8217;t really been inspiring me to do many
geeky projects lately. It&#8217;s been a long time since I&#8217;ve spent a weekend
building a file server to store the household&#8217;s files (and setting up all the
laptops and desktops to back themselves up to said fileserver, with an off-site
backup).  Hmm sounds like a project&#8230;.but I digress. I haven&#8217;t installed 6
different Linux/Solaris/BSD operating systems on a single computer in years. I
haven&#8217;t learned a new programming language just for fun in almost a decade (C#
at work doesn&#8217;t count, it&#8217;s not really that fun).  Am I losing my geek-ability?</p>

<p>No, this was the project that spurred my inner geek to its former glory.
Within a day, I had laid out a basic data model, selected a framework (I
settled on <a href="http://djangoproject">Django</a>, but I gave node.js+<a href="http://meteor.com">meteor</a> some
serious thought), and had the data prototyped and available in Django&#8217;s admin
tool for her to look at.  She gave me some feedback and showed me an example of
the way they currently work, so 24 hours later I had refined my data model and
had her take a second look at the admin tool with the new information and data
schema.  She gave me some more feedback and tweaks and I was ready to implement
them immediately, much to her chagrin.  She wanted me to put the laptop down
and spend time with her.  ;-)</p>

<p>I realized quickly that I had flown too high and was going to crash into the
sun.  She loved the work that I had done, and was appreciative of how quickly I
had a working protoype, but was also alarmed at my ferver to keep working on
this non-stop.  I don&#8217;t think a non-geek can understand the hold that a new
project has on a geek.  For the first few days, it is all we can think about.
After that, we slow down and take a more measured approach.  I also don&#8217;t think
that a non-geek can understand that the &#8220;work&#8221; that we do at home is more fun
for us than the &#8220;work&#8221; we do at work (even though it is usually the same kind
of &#8220;work&#8221;). I know she doesn&#8217;t want to come home and bow music scores all
night, but she can&#8217;t understand how I can work all day and still have the
mental energy to come home and get on the computer at night.</p>

<p>I guess I will need to take things a bit slower and pace myself.  My inner geek
must be balanced with the needs of my wonderful wife!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[It's the little things in life]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/30/its-the-little-things-in-life/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-30T08:19:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/30/its-the-little-things-in-life</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Ubuntu has a project that they call their &#8220;One Hundred Paper Cuts&#8221;, where
people list the little minor annoyances that detract them from truly enjoying
using Ubuntu.  You know, the little rough edges that annoy you for about two
seconds every time you rub against them.  Add that up and 2 seconds a day for
days or weeks or years can get you quite annoyed.  Interested developers or
uses can then go in and tackle these paper cuts to smooth out the tiny rough
edges.  I think other large projects could follow this model.</p>

<p>Today I rubbed up against one of these paper cuts in one of my least favorite
tools ever: Microsoft Active Directory Users and Computers.  I have to use this tool on a
daily basis and this paper cut gets me ever damn time: when you click on the
&#8220;search&#8221; button and the search dialog pops up, the focus is not on the &#8220;Name&#8221;
field (the first text entry field) but on the &#8220;Find Now&#8221; button.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The most common use case for this dialog box is to search for a user&#8217;s account.
Why put the focus on the &#8220;Find Now&#8221; button?  All this does is add one extra
mouse click to the workflow.  &#8220;One extra mouse click, what are you worried
about that for? You must be on crack.&#8221;, you might say.  Well, I have to say that
extra mouse click multiple times a day really adds up.</p>

<p><em>Every time</em> I need to use this tool, my mind is intent on getting the search
dialog up and entering the user&#8217;s id or name to find them and work on their
account.  Every time I click the search button, my hand goes back from the
mouse to the keyboard and I start typing, and every time I have to take my hand
off the keyboard, back to the mouse, and click in the &#8220;Name&#8221; field.</p>

<p>It seems trivial to someone else, but this little paper cut gets me several
times a day, every day, for years now.  Maybe once we upgrade to a newer
version of Active Directory the ADUC tool will have this bug fixed.  I can&#8217;t
understand how it got there in the first place.</p>

<p>Developers!  Use your own products and note the little things that annoy you
about them.  This will only help your end users in the long run.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[played an excellent gig last Friday]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/played-an-excellent-gig-last-friday/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T17:15:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/played-an-excellent-gig-last-friday</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>We had a great show on Friday night at the oddly named &#8220;Cocky Rooster&#8221; bar in
Comfort, TX.  This is a pretty cool little hole-in-the-wall bar with some
really laid back and fun people.  There were some regulars that remembered us
from last time so that was pretty cool.</p>

<p>I have to say, I haven&#8217;t even picked up a pair of sticks since the last gig and
I was surprised at how well I played.  Everthing just seemed to flow out of me
and I felt that I sounded better than I have in a while.  Sometimes you just need
a break to get the juices flowing again.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fedora is working great so far]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/fedora-is-working-great-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T16:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/fedora-is-working-great-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, my migration from Ubuntu to Fedora on my workstation at work went
pretty smoothly.  There were a few hiccups (like my SATA to USB dock
decided to act up at one point and I had to wait until I scrounged up
another internal SATA cable to plug the old drive into the motherboard)
and Fedora had some strangeness at first, but after a <code>yum
upgrade</code> or two everything was a-ok.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The main bit of install-time strangeness was that I had to edit the
<code>/etc/sysconfig/network</code> file by hand to set my static IP
instead of DHCP. The network manager utility tried to load into the system tray
the first time I logged in, but it wouldn&#8217;t come up at first (the error message
said that it wasn&#8217;t compatible with this version of Fedora any more??), but the
next day after a <code>yum upgrade</code>it popped up in the system tray at the
top where it was supposed to be.  That was pretty weird.</p>

<p>I must say, I am liking Gnome 3 very much.  I got used to some of the Unity
keybindings but the Gnome 3 ones match exactly how I work.  I use a 2 monitor
configuration and I keep a Byobu terminal open on one screen at all times,
which is exactly how Gnome 3 does it.  I also prefer to have a single row of
virtual screens instead of the 2x2 grid.  I rarely used the virtual screen
feature of Unity until recently, but the Gnome 3 layout makes way more sense.</p>

<p>Canonical has done a great job with Unity, but Gnome 3 seems to fit my workflow
a lot better.  I also didn&#8217;t like how with the latest version of Ubuntu, the
Unity menu would take forever to come up.  Fedora with Gnome 3 feels so much
snappier on the same hardware.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[.Net wierdness]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/22/dot-net-wierdness/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-22T21:34:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/22/dot-net-wierdness</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Argh.  Every time I use a Microsoft programming tool or library, I am first
initially amazed at how slick it is and how it solves 90% of my problems for
me.  The problem is that the other 10% is so hidden away and obscure that it is
actually harder to use if they just decided not to hide the underlying
functionality.</p>

<p>Maybe the documentation for the StringDictionary Collection is just not
telling what I want to hear, or maybe I&#8217;m not understanding it.  I can&#8217;t
tell whether there are any actual accessors for the keys and values other than iterating through the list.</p>

<p>Sigh.  I&#8217;m just whining because dictionaries in .Net aren&#8217;t first class data
citizens like in python or ruby.  More work tomorrow.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[the 'other' Mark McCoy]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/17/the-other-mark-mccoy/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T17:11:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/17/the-other-mark-mccoy</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>By the way, if you search Google for my name, you might find markmccoy.com (not
linking it, you can go there if you want but I don&#8217;t recommend it).  <strong>That is
not me.</strong>  That guy is a crazy conspiracy theorist and probably my exact
opposite.  Maybe he&#8217;s a doppelganger who has a goatee (Evil Me).</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[welcome to my new site]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/17/welcome-to-my-new-site/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-17T16:59:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/17/welcome-to-my-new-site</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Hey there, I&#8217;m setting up my new blog site. It will be dedicated to the things that I am interested in, primarily music and computers.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
