<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: linux | Musically Geeky]]></title>
  <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/categories/linux/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://markmccoy.us/"/>
  <updated>2013-03-28T17:17:50-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://markmccoy.us/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[Mark McCoy]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[fedora is working great so far]]></title>
    <link href="http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/fedora-is-working-great-so-far/"/>
    <updated>2013-01-28T16:45:00-06:00</updated>
    <id>http://markmccoy.us/blog/2013/01/28/fedora-is-working-great-so-far</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>Well, my migration from Ubuntu to Fedora on my workstation at work went
pretty smoothly.  There were a few hiccups (like my SATA to USB dock
decided to act up at one point and I had to wait until I scrounged up
another internal SATA cable to plug the old drive into the motherboard)
and Fedora had some strangeness at first, but after a <code>yum
upgrade</code> or two everything was a-ok.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>The main bit of install-time strangeness was that I had to edit the
<code>/etc/sysconfig/network</code> file by hand to set my static IP
instead of DHCP. The network manager utility tried to load into the system tray
the first time I logged in, but it wouldn't come up at first (the error message
said that it wasn't compatible with this version of Fedora any more??), but the
next day after a <code>yum upgrade</code>it popped up in the system tray at the
top where it was supposed to be.  That was pretty weird.</p>

<p>I must say, I am liking Gnome 3 very much.  I got used to some of the Unity
keybindings but the Gnome 3 ones match exactly how I work.  I use a 2 monitor
configuration and I keep a Byobu terminal open on one screen at all times,
which is exactly how Gnome 3 does it.  I also prefer to have a single row of
virtual screens instead of the 2x2 grid.  I rarely used the virtual screen
feature of Unity until recently, but the Gnome 3 layout makes way more sense.</p>

<p>Canonical has done a great job with Unity, but Gnome 3 seems to fit my workflow
a lot better.  I also didn't like how with the latest version of Ubuntu, the
Unity menu would take forever to come up.  Fedora with Gnome 3 feels so much
snappier on the same hardware.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
